<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><listPerson xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><person xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="STO05" sex="1"><persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/><forename xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">John Hurford</forename><surname xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Stone</surname><addName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/></persName><birth xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1763"><placeName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/></birth><death xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1818"/><occupation xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">printer</occupation><occupation xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">reformer</occupation><note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="editorial"><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Godwin's early contacts with 'Stone' do seem plausibly associated with 
    John Hurford Stone, a parishioner of Price and disciple of Priestley, a supporter of the French 
    Revolution, and someone who offered to help the French ambassador negotiate with Britain 
    to prevent war. </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">John Hurford Stone left for Paris in April 1792.    He divorced his wife in France and had a long affair with <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="WIL01">Helen Maria Williams</persName>. He died in Paris in 1818.
    Alger  in <title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Englishmen in the French Revolution</title> , suggests that Stone returned to England between February 
    and May 1793, and was incarcerated in the Luxembourg for seventeen days in October 1793.  Thereafter there is no suggestion that he returned to England, and the fact that his intercepted correspondence
    resulted in a prosecution for High Treason for his brother William, suggests that he was under surveilance and would have been arrested had he returned. </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">If the early entries to 'Stone' in the diary are to John Hurford, these would leave  unexplained the entries for:
   1792-06-15, although this has been coded for Stone on the grounds that when he left in 
   April 1792 he probably did not  believe he was leaving the country for good and it is likely he returned at some point to settle his affairs (and the context is right).
   Howver, it is possible that this (indeed, all the) Stone entry refers to William Stone, John Hurford's brother, who was 
   tried for High Treason in January 1796, following the interception of correspondence (in 1793 and 1794) from John Hurford Stone..
   However, it is surprising that Godwin seems to have no involvement with Stone around the time of the trial, 
   and William was basically a Middlesex Coal merchant, rather than a literary figure, or someone associated with literary circles. Also, 
   the treason case linked Stone to William Jackson, an Irish revolutionary, but there is no evidence connecting the one possible 
   entry for William Jackson (9 February 1794, at Horne Tooke's - although the prosecution states that Jackson did not arrive in 
   the country from Hamburg until 26 February 1794, so that identification is uncertain) with any Stone entry, which also casts doubt on the Stone being William.
   Alger suggests that William Stone left England to join his brother in France, but gives no date.  It cannot be before March 1796 and there is an issue of whether he could have 
   been granted a passport (Godwin was turned down during the Peace of Amiens), or whether he would have had to wait  for tensions to subside, or could have slipped across via Germany.  
   It is certainly possible that the entries for 1793, 1795 and 1797 are all to William Stone - just as it is possible that the earlier entries are also to him. But there is no supporting evidence
   for the attribution and we have left later entries uncoded.</p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> There is also nothing to connect William Stone, or John Hurford Stone, with the <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="STO03 STO04">John and William Stone</persName> 
    who show an interest in Godwin's business in 1815.
    It is possible that some of the later Stone entries relate to the 'Stone surgeon' whom Godwin notes in 1814.  The following have been 
    left uncoded, despite the possible connection to William Stone.  We have 
    been unable to identify William's date of death or his career subsequent to his trial for treason (other than a court case immediately 
    following concerning a bond (see <title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">The Times</title> for 25 February 1796.
    # 1793-08-06
    # 1795-01-31
    # 1795-03-15
    # 1797-06-06
    # 1826-12-31 </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">    St Clair speculates that <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="STO03 STO04">John and William Stone</persName>  were the radicals John Hurford Stone (lover of Helen Maria Williams) and his brother William.
    We have ruled this out on the basis that  John Hurford Stone was based in Paris, would have had difficulty in getting into England during the war,  had  been declared bankrupt in 1813, and would 
    most likely have been liable to prosecution associated with his brother's trial for High Treason in 1796.</p></note><bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="printedbook">St Clair, pp. 369-70.</bibl><bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="other"><title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">DNB</title>.</bibl><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="appearancesInDiary"><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1788"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1789"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1790"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1790-02-01" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1790-02-13" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1791"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1791-12-03" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1792"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1792-06-15" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1793"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1794"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1795"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1796"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1797"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1798"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1799"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1800"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1801"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1802"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1803"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1804"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1805"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1806"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1807"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1808"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1809"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1810"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1811"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1812"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1813"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1814"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1815"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1816"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1817"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1818"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1819"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1820"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1821"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1822"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1823"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1824"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1825"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1826"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1827"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1828"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1829"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1830"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1831"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1832"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1833"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1834"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1835"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1836"/></ab></person></listPerson>