<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><listPerson xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><person xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="VAU99" sex="1"><persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><roleName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/><forename xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/><surname xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Vaughan</surname><addName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/></persName><birth xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1000"><placeName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> </placeName></birth><death xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1000"/><occupation xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/><occupation xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"/><note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="editorial"><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Several of these entries probably relate to Samuel Vaughan (1720–1802), a London merchant, and his son Benjamin Vaughan, (1751–1835), diplomatist 
    and political reformer. It is not possible to be sure which is being indicated, and the presence of other Vaughans adds additional complications.</p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"> In  the 1796 notes Godwin indicates that he meets meet Samuel Vaughan (the father of Benjamin) who dies in 1802, in 1782; he notes 
    (in the 1796 list in the diary) meeting B. Vaughan in 1779; and  he notes meeting <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU01">Felix Vaughan</persName> (1766-1799) in 1793. 
    He also notes meeting <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU02">W Vaughan</persName> in 1790, 1792, and then 1814, 1818, and 1821 
    There are separate codes for each of: Felix, William and <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU03">W H Vaughan</persName> which are 
    used when the initials are used, or, more exceptionally, where it is thought that the 
    contact indicates that it is a particular Vaughan (as in the Vaughan at the Treason 
    Trials, where Felix would have been present and Benjamin out of the country).
    Early entries of Vaughan are coded generically under this codename; all F Vaughan are coded as Felix Vaughan, and with Felix Vaughan being used for
    Vaughan entries if we have independent corroboration of his presence, (as at the Treason Trials). We
    believe that some Vaughans without initial  are Benjamin Vaughan; some may be Samuel
    Vaughan, and some may be Felix Vaughan. It is possible that William Vaughan might also be
    entered without an initial on some occasions. The early W Vaughan entries are coded as William
    Vaughan. The later ones may well be W H Vaughan’s and we are coded as such. We do not have a
    plausible Vaughan for entries between 1807 and 1812, and the continuation of plain Vaughan after
    this date suggests that these refer to another person and so these are also coded as VAU99. </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Samuel Vaughan (1720–1802), was an active reformer as a member of the Society
    of the Supporters of the Bill of Rights in the 1760s and a friend of John Wilkes and John Horne
    Tooke. He was also a member of the Club of Honest Whigs, the meetings of which Benjamin
    sometimes attended, whereby he associated with the likes of Priestley, Richard Price, and James
    Burgh. </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Vaughan, Benjamin (1751–1835), was the eldest of eleven children of Samuel Vaughan (1720–1802),  Educated at Hackney and Warrington with his
    brother William under Joseph Priestley, he became acquainted with
    Benjamin Franklin in 1767.  Lord
    Shelburne employed him as an adviser and private secretary, notably in Paris during the
    Anglo-American peace negotiations of 1782–3. In 1783 Vaughan returned to London; he entertained
    on a regular basis reform-minded men like Price, Priestley, Thomas Paine, and Samuel Romilly.
    Aftyer 1789, he made a number of visits to Paris and he wrote
    a number of reform orientated pamphlets. Elected MP for Calne, he barely spoke in the House. In May
    1794, following the arrest of William Stone and the seizure of his correspondence Vaughan was
    summoned in to appear before the privy council. He fled to France eventually joing his family in 1797
    in America.  Godwin notes meeting B(enjamin) Vaughan in 1779 (1796 journal list), but he has left
    the country by May 1794.  Nonetheless, it is possible that some 1793 and 1794 entries refer to 
    Benjamin rather than to Felix (and we have accordingly left the issue open by coding them as VAU99).  </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU01">Felix Vaughan</persName> (Mark Philp, <title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Godwin’s Political Justice</title>, p. 244) 1766-1799, helped to draft LCS regulations. He was one of Horne
    Tooke’s defence counsel (St Clair), and a defender of Eaton. Thought by some to be the
    illegitimate son of Tooke, but there is no evidence to support this; but he was very close to
    Tooke and left him his money when he died young in 1799. He also travelled widely in France in
    the early years of the French Revolution returning to England in 1793. </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU02">W Vaughan</persName> – entered as such in the 1790s and also in the 1820s, is probably  William Vaughan, (1752–1850),
    promoter of the London docks, the second son of Samuel
    Vaughan (1720–1802)</p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU03"> W H Vaughan</persName> seems to be distinct – probably Vaughan, William Hasleham County: London Town: London Address(es): Orange Ct, Soho Book Trades: Stationer
    Non-Book Trade: Trading Dates: 1818 - 1830 Biographical Dates: 1818 (before) - 1830 This
    suggests that the early entries to Vaughan are likely to be to B or S (most likely B?) – and
    that F Vaughan and W Vaughan would be used disjunctively until at least May 1794, when B Vaughan
    has left the country. If, however, B Vaughan is the default, tthere are a number of plain Vaughan’s
    after May 1794 that are simply not accounted for. Between 1798 and 1807 no Vaughan’s are
    recorded – and the Vaughans recorded after seem to be on a different footing – they call on
    Godwin or are called on by him. This could mean that there is a further Vaughan, seen on a
    regular basis between the 1807 and 1820, from which occasional meetings with W Vaughan are then
    distinguished. However, the evidence from the Diary suggests that the 1812 W H Vaughan is a
    reference to the stationer, and further references after 1814 given as W Vaughan, may also be
    references to him, given that they are associated with others who could be people in the
    publishing and bookselling industry (eg: Hunter, Miles, Murray, R Sharp, Sturmy, O Rees). But it
    is unlikely that this Vaughan accounts for the plain ‘Vaughan’s’ between 1807 and 1818, since
    the introduction of W H Vaughan in 1812 suggests otherwise. </p><p xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Finally, there is a puzzle about the <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU04">Mrs Vaughan</persName> who stays during Mary Wollstoncrafts labour, and who may, or may not, be related to 
      the Vaughan family and about <persName xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" key="VAU05">PV</persName>who appears immediately after Mrs Vaughan. Clemit's 
      edition of Godwin's Letters, Volume 1, suggests that PV refers to Petty Vaughan, the third son of Benjamin and Sarah Vaughan, and while this is possible it is also 
      possible that Mrs Vaughan is in fact PV, since when she ceases to appear in the diary the initials appear for the first time. In the July of 1797, Godwin seems to have read
      <dText xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="read" corresp="te0764">Vaughan's Letters</dText>, possibly from Addington (who calls the previous day, and to whom he refers in a 
      note to Wollstonecraft saying he does not mean to return them to him today (4 July 1797).  We have coded these as Benjamin Vaughan's Letters on France and Poland, but this must be open to doubt. Godwin
      reads the letters regularly until 7 July and only finally finishes them on 25 July.  While reading them he also has entries on 6 July, 19 July and 18th August 'Write to V' (and on the latter he also refers 
      again to the Letters).  This suggests that he is compiling a long letter to Vaughan on the Letters, which he did not complete until mid-August. But the identification of the text sits uncomfortably with 
      the suggestion that these are in fact Mrs Vaughan's Letters, lent by Addington - which is the upshot of 
      Wollstonecraft and Godwin's exchange on 4 July 1797.  But, if these are indeed Mrs Vaughan's letters, it seems very unlikely that she is Sarah Vaughan, (Benjamin's wife), since the evidence 
      points to her being in America in July.  Moreover, there is nothing to suggest that she has much connection with the Vaughan family </p></note><bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="printedbook">Mark Philp, <title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">Godwin’s Political Justice</title> (London: Duckworth, 1986)</bibl><bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="printedbook">Pamela Clemit, ed., <title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">The Letters of Wiliam Godwin Volume 1 1778-1797</title>, Oxford, 2011</bibl><bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="printedbook">St Clair</bibl><bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="other"><title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">DNB</title></bibl><bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="other"><title xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">The British Book Trade Index</title></bibl><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="appearancesInDiary"><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1788"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1789"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1790"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1790-02-13" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1791"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1792"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1793"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1793-12-08" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1793-12-15" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1794"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1794-02-09" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1794-05-18" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1794-05-25" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1794-06-13" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1794-11-13" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1795"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1795-03-01" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1795-05-03" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1795-08-30" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1796"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1796-01-31" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1796-09-18" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1797"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1797-08-23" n="notVenue" type="ah"/><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1797-08-25" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1798"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1798-05-27" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1799"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1800"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1801"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1802"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1803"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1804"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1805"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1806"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1807"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1808"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1809"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1810"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1811"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1812"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1812-02-03" n="venue" type="nah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1813"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1813-05-13" n="venue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1814"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1814-06-02" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1815"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1816"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1816-06-14" n="notVenue" type="ah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1817"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1818"><date xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" when="1818-11-13" n="venue" type="nah"/></ab><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1819"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1820"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1821"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1822"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1823"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1824"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1825"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1826"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1827"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1828"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1829"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1830"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1831"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1832"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1833"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1834"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1835"/><ab xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" n="1836"/></ab></person></listPerson>